在上一集里
Previously on Transformers: Prime
“破坏者”宇宙大帝之血
It's as if the blood of Unicron the Destroyer
好像流遍了我浑身的经脉
flows through my veins.
可那会是黑暗能量吗？
Dark Energon?
那东西非常罕见 几乎搜索不到
It's so scarce as to be virtually non-existent.
有生人介入
Contact with civilians.
他们的安全由我们保护
We're protecting them.
把这个福勒给我带来
Fetch me this Fowler.
告诉我汽车人基地的位置
Tell me the location of the Autobot base.
是求救信号
It's an SOS.
- 糟了\N- 糟了
- Scrap.\N- Scrap.
觉醒吧 我的战士们！
Rise, my army!
请看 这就是传说中的…黑暗能量！
Behold, the power of Dark Energon!
威震天亵渎了\N我们共同先祖的长眠之地…他于心何忍！
Megatron has desecrated the resting place of our fallen ancestors... and his own!
连死人也免不了被他推上战场
Not even the dead are free from his war-mongering.
终于 我感受到和黑暗能量共生的妙处了
At last, symbiosis, I can feel it.
我可以完全控制我的军队
I possess complete control over my army.
摧毁他们！
Destroy them!
擎天柱 如果我们的对手已经死过一次
Optimus, if our combatants are already deceased
我们能再“杀死”他们吗？
How can we possibly defeat them?
救护车 撤退！
Ratchet, retreat!
你先返回基地！
Bridge yourself back to base!
不 我要和你共进退 擎天柱
No, I shall stand with you, Optimus.
战斗结束后 你可能需要治疗
You may require a medic when this is over with.
我建议 把他们解剖
I recommend dissection.
切得越碎越好！
The smaller the pieces, the better!
好主意 老朋友
Sound advice, old friend.
我已掌控了黑暗能量
I have mastered Dark Energon.
如果你战死 擎天柱
When you fall, Optimus
你也会成为我的部下
you too, shall join my army.
上车 快！
Get in, now!
谢谢 隔板
Thanks, Bulkhead.
是啊 谢谢
Yea, thanks.
你…你们怎么来了？
What... what are you doing here?
我们担心神子
We were worried about Miko.
你看到她了吗？
Have you seen her?
她长什么样？
What's she look like?
全体下车
Everyone out.
这一次 拜托 在这儿等着！
And this time, please, wait here!
神子在哪儿？
Where's Miko?
神子？！
Miko?
我吐在脚垫上了
I heaved on your floor mats.
抱歉
Sorry! Ugh...
提醒我 以后别坐过山车了
Remind me never to do that again.
他们把我们忘了吗？
Think they forgot about us?
我又要吐了
I'm gonna heave again.
把他们扔进监牢
Bring them to the brig.
红蜘蛛指挥官把另一个人类也关在那儿
Commander Starscream has keeping the other human there.
大黄蜂！
Bumblebee!
感谢你们清理了大门口
Appreciate you cleared the front door for us.
但进攻霸天虎战舰可不是娱乐活动
But storming the Decepticon warship was not on the activities list.
我们像在娱乐吗？
Tell me about it.
- 自己人！\N- 还用说！
- Friendly!\N- Hello!
竟然带人类出来打仗？
Brought the humans, huh?
你来试试撇下他们看看！
You try getting them to stay behind!
我们得找到福勒 再把孩子们带出去
We need to find Fowler and get these kids outta here.
他在监牢
Uh, he's in the brig.
我亲爱的福勒探员
My dear Agent Fowler.
你一定知道 汽车人已经把你抛弃了
You do realize the Autobots have abandoned you.
我是你现在唯一的依靠
I am the only one you can rely upon now.
快把我想知道的告诉我
So, tell me what I want to know
否则…
or...
求你了 别这样
Please, no more.
他们在…政府的秘密基地
They're in secret government base.
说下去
Go on.
还有呢？
Yes?
那是个旧炼钢厂
In the old steel mill
好像在嘉年华游乐园地下吧？
was it under that carnival's fun house?
去看看外面怎么回事！
Someone find out what is going on out there!
擎天柱 长时间接触黑暗能量
Ugh, Optimus, this prolonged exposure to Dark Energon
我们会吃不消的
is sapping our strength.
我们必须背水一战
We cannot falter now.
擎天柱！
Optimus! Eah...
这么多年过去了 擎天柱
After all these years, Optimus
宝刀不老嘛！
still at the top of your game!
我的将士们 干掉他们！
My legion, finish them!
安全
Clear.
在这儿等着
Wait in here.
他们行动缓慢 容易受到攻击
They're slowing us down, and they're easy targets.
只要他们不乱跑
They'll be alright in here
就不会有麻烦
as long as they stay put.
刚才真是太吓人了
That was intense.
现在不吓人吗？
Was?
我们被卷进来 都是因为你
It's your fault that we're stuck in this intensity.
你是怎么想的 神子？
What were you thinking, Miko?
是我让你跟来的吗？
Did I ask you to follow me?
是你要组建乐队的
You wanted us to be a band.
乐队不是应该“步调一致”吗？
Doesn't that usually mean "playing together"?
那我要考虑单飞了！
Well, maybe I decided to go solo!!
那我还是要关心你的安全！
Well, maybe I have some regard for your safety!
噢 对不起 你也叫擎天柱吗？
Oh, I'm sorry, is your name Optimus?
有隔板保护我就够了 谢谢关心！
You can leave my protection to Bulkhead, thank you very much!
别闹了！你们俩闭嘴！
Stop it! Both of you!
噢 嘿嘿嘿 拉夫 拉夫 没事的
Oh, hey hey hey, Raf, Raf, it's... it's ok.
是啊 我们不会有事的
Yea, we're gonna be fine.
我们的搭档会回来救我们的
Our bots will come back for us.
是啊 他们会把我们送回家
Yea. They're gonna take us home.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
嘿 拉夫
Hey, Raf
你能看懂那个吗？
what do you make of that?
是重要资料
It's important.
非常重要
Really important.
睁开眼 你这可怜的肉团！
Wake up, you pathetic lump of flesh!
奶奶？该吃饼干了吗？
Mmm... Grandma? Is it cookie time?
怎么了？！
Well?
别太心急！
Not so fast!
我不想动粗
I wouldn't.
噢 我可没准儿…
Oh, but I MIGHT...
必须把它交给擎天柱
We got to get this to Optimus.
说不定这是太空玉米片的食谱呢
How do you know it isn't just a recipe for space nachos?
我一看就知道那是数学问题
I know math when I see it.
那可是个信息量巨大的方程式
And that is one serious equation.
你可以…下载它吗？
Can you... download it?
我有个闪存盘
I got a flash drive.
但这里好像没有接口
But I don't see anywhere to plug it in.
这东西太外星化了
This tech is way alien.
现在 我要带福勒探员先走一步
Now, Agent Fowler and I will take our leave.
恶魔说 耶！
The evil says "yep!"
神子 拍张照片！
Miko, take a picture!
好主意！
Great idea!
嘿 说你呐！
Hey, you!
不是它 是那个！
Not of that, of that!
快 快 快！
Go, go, go!
我说过 别乱跑！
I told you to stay put!
我喜欢馅饼
I like pie.
可以去吃馅饼吗？
Can we stop for pie?
你们找到福勒了！
You found Fowler!
好哎！
ROCK ON!
干得漂亮 擎天柱！
Bravo, Optimus!
这只是个序幕
Though this is but a prelude.
你最好为正戏保存一点实力！
You may wish to save your strength for the main event!
你不会得逞的 威震天
You will not prevail, Megatron.
除非我体内的能量枯竭！
Not while energon still flows
through my veins!
来日方长 我体内的黑暗能量也长流不息
Fit in, for this Dark Energon which flows through mine.
如果这还不算威震天的正戏
If this wasn't Megatron's in game
什么才算呢？
what is?
你们到底怎么了？
What happened to you guys anyway?
我们碰上了一队不死的塞博特恩战士
We engaged an army of undead Cybertronian warriors.
僵尸？
Zombies?
你们打僵尸竟然不带我？
You fought zombies and I missed it?
隔板
Bulkhead
让人类跟你一起参加战斗 可不是个明智的决定
you exercised extremely poor judgement at allowing the humans to accompany you.
不会有下次了 擎天柱
It won't happen again, Optimus
我…我发誓
I promise.
那不关隔板的事
But it wasn't Bulkhead's fault.
神子 别说了！
Miko, please!
你们看
And check it out.
这才叫侦察！
Recon!
救护车 你来看
Umm... Ratchet, have a look.
这对威震天来说可能是重要资料
It could be of importance to Megatron.
喔 威震天回来了？
Wow, Megatron's back?
是个坏消息 对吧？
That's really bad news, right?
我…看不懂
I... don't understand.
噢
Oops.
那个虎子想把拉夫炸飞
That's the Con who'd tried to blow Raf away.
他还没来得及动手
At least that's what it look like
隔板就三下五除二把它解决了
before Bulkhead rearrange his grill.
神子 拉夫差点没命
Miko, Raf was almost killed!
这可不是闹着玩的
This isn't a game
你那死脑袋什么时候才会明白？
when do you gonna get that through your fixed skull?
嗯 我们全都差点没命 杰克
Umm, we were all almost killed, Jack.
你 我 拉夫
You, me, Raf
还有他们！
even them!
如果和汽车人在一起 每天都有生命危险
Well, if this was just an average day with the Autobots
那我不干了
then I don't wanna be a part of it.
彻底退出
Not any more.
杰克
Jack
我们从没想过让你去冒险
putting you in harm's way was never our intent.
可是 生命悬于一线的不止是你们三个了
However, it is no longer the safety of you three that is at risk
而是全体人类
but the safety of all human kind.
如果你们要离开 我们会尊重这个决定
We will respect your decision if you wish to leave.
别依依不舍了 门在这儿
No point in long good-byes. Here's the door.
走吧 拉夫
Come on, Raf.
我要留下来 杰克 学校见
I'll be ok, Jack. See you at school.
好的
Sure thing.
我知道 你们不存在
I know, you don't exist.
别逼我去抓你回来
Don't make me hunt you down.
求你了 威震天陛下 我没料到…
Please, Lord Megatron, I meant no... Ah...
我告诉过你要等我的命令！
I ordered you to await my command!
可你干的蠢事弄垮了我的飞船！
Instead, your mindless agenda resulted in the disabling of my ship!
还耽误了我的大事！
And the delay of my plans!
我没别的想法 主人
My intentions were pure, master.
我只是想帮您除掉擎天柱！
I only wanted you to be rid of Optimus!
除了我 没人能除掉擎天柱
No one rids me of Optimus Prime but me.
你明白吗
Do you understand
明白吗？
do you?
威震天陛下 我会处理好的 我发誓！
Lord Megatron, I will make things right, I swear!
我知道怎么能让您的计划回到正轨！
I know how to set your plans back on course!
说清楚点 红蜘蛛
Explain, Starscream
别磨蹭
quickly.
我现在明白了 你要赶回家修车
Now I understand why you had to rush home.
你没有更刺激的事可做吗 神子？
Don't you have something more exciting to do, Miko?
看来 你就在这儿混日子 对吧？
So, this is where you hang, huh?
在东京老家的时候
Back home in Tokyo
我有可爱的父母和两只纯种猫
I have loving parents and two purebred cats
琪琪和叮当
Chi Chi and Ding Dong.
我去最好的学校 三岁就开始学钢琴
I went to the best school, to piano lessons since I was three.
挺好的嘛
How nice for you.
不 闷死了
No, how boring.
那不是我想要的
It wasn't me.
当时要转学到这儿 我高兴得不得了
Why do you think I jumped at the chance to transfer here?
因为内华达州贾斯帕是世界娱乐中心吗？
To Jasper, Navada
the entertainment capital of the world?
谁知道啊 唉 那些人撒谎
Yeah, well, the bros sure lied.
学钢琴其实也挺有意思的
Piano lessons were starting to look pretty good, in fact.
然后 就发生了过去几天的事情
But then, the last couple of days happened.
你到底想说什么？
Do you have a point?
你觉得呢？
You bet?
你今天做的我都看见了
I saw what you did today
你救了拉夫
when you saved Raf
还救了我
when you came to save me.
这些年我一直学着要负责任
I've been raised to be responsible
对功课 对妈妈 对工作负责任
to my schoolwork, to my mom, my job.
哥们儿 听我说
Dude, hear me out.
你不是厨子
You're no fry cook
你是摇滚明星
you're a rock star.
别装平凡了 杰克
Stop pretending you're normal, Jack.
你绝对不是这种人
You'll never fit in.
你注定要干些大事
You were born to do so much more.
谢谢你 神子
Thanks, Miko.
但我觉得平凡更适合我
But I think normal suits me fine.
这不可能
It can't be.
擎天柱！
Optimus!
这些是时空漩涡发生器的技术资料
These are engineering specs for a space-time vortex generator.
威震天正在建造太空桥
Megatron's building a Space Bridge
也许他已经建成了
if he hasn't already.
他走得越早越好
The sooner he leaves, the better.
隔板 太空桥是个双向通道
Bulkhead, a Space Bridge runs in two directions.
威震天可能不是要离开地球
Megatron may not be using it to leave Earth
而是用它召集军队
but to bring through his conquering army.
那就是威震天所谓的正戏吗？
The main event Megatron referred to...
可是 唯一能让威震天召唤无数死人的地方是…
But the only place Megatron could possibly recruit that many fallen warriors...
一点没错…
Precisely...
塞博特恩
Cybertron.